so we were talking about emptyness and
then I I think when you're talking about
emptiness you have to ask one more
question which is so what's the use of
emptiness if everything is empty then
then how is that going to help me and
how is that going to help me help the
world you see what I mean and I thought
I'd talk about that today
so we were talking about emptiness if
you'd like to understand emptiness
quickly and correctly which is rare we
have to talk about a pen and that we can
say that when I show this to you and I
ask you what it is then you'll say a pen
when I show it to a dog they all just
chew on it they don't see it as a pen
when I leave this object on the couch
all the dogs leave the room all the
humans leave the room at that point if I
ask you is it a pen or is it a chew toy
then your mind correctly says well well
at that time it's really neither one
it's sort of up in the air which one
it's going to be depends on who walks in
the room first
so we can say that that the emptiness of
a pen means that this black cylinder is
something like a white movie screen it's
just available and that's its emptiness
think of emptiness as blankness or white
movie screen this and then it's a little
easier to understand so this is like a
white movie screen and and that dog is
gonna see it as a chew toy and a human
is going to see it as a pen so then if I
ask you a question if I say do you think
the pen when you look at a pen and you
see a pen do you think it's coming this
way or do you think it's coming this way
do you think do you think a pen when you
see a pen is coming this way or is the
pen coming this way and then the answer
is if you understand emptiness if you
understand what we just spoke about it
must be coming this way you see it must
be coming from me if the pen was coming
from its own side
if pen was like announcing itself and
yelling at me I'm a pen I'm a pen if it
were coming this way and then I showed
it to a dog then the dog would wouldn't
try to take in and they would try to use
it
right something I'd like to think they'd
be writing a poem to their dog
girlfriends you have a nice tail or
something like that but they don't they
don't feel it as a pen they don't see it
as a pen it means that the pen must be
coming this way the pen must be coming
from me it's like a blank white screen
but my mind fills in the screen in
essence then the pen is coming for me
how can you use that you see and then
and then you get into this idea which is
wrong people say just think positive you
know
if the pen is coming from you and let's
say the pen is out of ink
you need the pen really bad you have to
write something really important
somebody's phone number and then the pen
isn't working the pen is out of ink then
you would think or you would think oh if
I understand the emptiness of the pen I
could make a pen that has ink you seen I
mean just by wishing you see so the pen
is out of ink I hold the pen up I know
the pen is coming from my mind I close
my eyes I think more ink more ink more
ink and I'm wishing I'm wanting I am
praying that the pen should have more
ink you see and then I I finished
because I realized that the pen is
coming from me so if I just wanted or
wish that it had more ink then it should
have more ink if it's coming from me and
then you pray and you wish it could be
ink for a pen it could be a new job or a
promotion at work it could be that your
auntie and her breast cancer goes away
you can pray you can think you can wish
right and if it's coming from you then
shouldn't it change then you open your
eyes and you open the pen and then you
try to write with it and then you
realize it's still out of ink you see so
we can say that the pen must be coming
from the mind the pen is empty like a
white movie screen when I see a pen it
must be coming from my mind but we we
can be sure about one thing it's not a
voluntary
it's not that you can close your eyes
and you wish that the pen would be
something else
the pen is coming from your mind but
other forces are at work other energies
are at work you don't have a choice
about what you see something else in
your mind is forcing you to see what you
see can we find out what it is can we
use it can we change it and then we
could create objects we could make a
different world at will and that's the
thing we have to talk about next